# Casey Golightly Chamberlain

#### Full Stack Web Developer · Software Engineer

1505 Commons Ford Pl, Apex, NC, 27539

(385)-201-5044 | caseygchamberlain@gmail.com | Portfolio | GitHub | LinkedIn

"One day or day one. You decide."

# **Summary**

Recent full stack web developer graduate with previous analyst experience. Professionally educated at the University of Utah. Graduated from the University's Coding Bootcamp in the spring of 2022. Strengths in teamwork, meeting deadlines, creativity, and self reliance. Known to be a hyper focused and determined individual passionate about developing full stack web applications.

My technical experience as an international shipping analyst for one of "America's Best Midsize Employers" (Forbes), has taught me the importance of the corporate environment and communication. My past experience makes me a strong addition as a developer with a mindset geared towards the small details and the user.

## **Skills**

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- MySQL
- Express.js

- React.js
- Node.js
- Heroku
- Bootstrap
- jQuery

- Handlebars.js
- GraphQL
- MongoDB
- Git

# **Work Experience**

# **Lightly LLC**

Raleigh, NC

Jan. 2023 - Present

Founder, CEO, & Software Engineer

- Freelance web developer.
- Design and code modern and professional front-end web applications for clients' needs.
- Successfully communicate and consult with clients about projects' scope, vision, and functionality.
- Adhere to SCRUM and AGILE methodologies.

#### **doTERRA**

#### Pleasant Grove, UT

### Australia/New Zealand Shipping Analyst

Jun. 2019 - Dec. 2022

- Communicate with the Operations department in the head office of Australia to ensure inventory and shipping performance regarding warehouse and carrier services.
- Subject matter expert regarding all domestic and international shipments between the United States of America, Australia, and New Zealand.
- 10+ Top Adherence awards.
- 5 MVP awards.

#### **Brian Head Resort**

Brian Head, UT

Nov. 2019 - Apr. 2020

**Lead Lift Operator** 

- Team leader of 3-4 lift operators.
- Closely work with mechanics to ensure safe ski lift operations.
- Closely work with ski patrol to ensure mountain and customer safety.

# **Honors & Awards**

2022	Web Coding Bootcamp Program, University of Utah
2022	Coding Bootcamp Full Stack Developer, Credly
2018	Varsity Track & Field, American Fork High School
2017	Varsity Cross Country, American Fork High School
2016	Varsity Cross Country, American Fork High School
2016	Eagle Scout, Boy Scouts of America

#### **Education**

#### **University of Utah**

#### Certificate, Full Stack Web Development

 A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Git, jQuery, Bootstrap, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js, and React.js.

#### **American Fork High School**

#### Diploma, Honors

- Team captain of nationally ranked cross country team.
- French club.

Casey Golightly Chamberlain · Résumé